[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b38", "question": "What Blue Collar Comedy Tour comedian is known for his routine concerning \"Tater Salad\"?", "answer": "Ron White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66b3a52a821ff76ae8b0d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph\"?", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6002433f4be4723ccac22193", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Russian-American author Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8657ec223966ae8f880f", "question": "\"TGS with Tracy Jordan\" is a fictional sketch-comedy show that is an integral part of which series?", "answer": "\"30 Rock\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b231", "question": "What kind of animal attacked Jimmy Carter during an April 1979 fishing trip?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe1", "question": "What is the literal translation of the Greek word \"Utopia\"?", "answer": "No-place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5971df3a89261e916c8e09a7", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feccd3aec223966ae8f88aa", "question": "What is the name of the event where tributes are chosen for \"The Hunger Games\"?", "answer": "The Reaping", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c2084f032c0db195b47d", "question": "Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590089e6cf842fa4c4ba968d", "question": "What was the first solo album released by Roger Waters?", "answer": "The Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eafa8f83302ff91e46495", "question": "The process of water changing to vapor is known as what?", "answer": "Evaporation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990b065b72eedf883a8c711", "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?", "answer": "TNT", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c98", "question": "Who was the Greek god of the sea?", "answer": "Poseidon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a528", "question": "Columbia University is located in which US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b787364247bf200fb873", "question": "Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?", "answer": "The Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af258f0b63e5727cf5a484a", "question": "Who sang the song \"Boom Boom Boom\"?", "answer": "The Outhere Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cddb5e347d002c297e4f3", "question": "Which 1960s singer/songwriter was voted \"Ugliest Man on Campus\" while attending college?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c9c3877e98cb977789fc", "question": "Pago Pago is the capital of which country", "answer": "American Samoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c2", "question": "What is Marilyn Monroe's real name?", "answer": "Norma Jeane Mortenson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c429", "question": "Which astronomer gave his name to a telescope launched into space in 1990?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c351", "question": "Which two scientists first proposed that DNA is structured in a double helix?", "answer": "James D. Watson and Francis Crick", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba4c4874c93a3298b2148", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Wales?", "answer": "Mount Snowdon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c234", "question": "What do Teal Pumpkins represent to Trick or Treaters?", "answer": "Non-Food Treats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339748", "question": "What British pop artist sings the songs \"Smile\" \"Hard out here\" and \"5 O' Clock\"", "answer": "Lily Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfb", "question": "What \"Fantasy Island\" actor ended up committing suicide?", "answer": "Herve Villechaize", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b588", "question": "When was Twitter first launched?", "answer": "2006", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be5", "question": "What year did Johnny Depp receive his Hollywood Walk of Fame star in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8c", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is James Smith?", "answer": "LL Cool J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c323", "question": "Name the continents entirely located in the Southern Hemisphere.", "answer": "Australia and Antarctica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a873", "question": "What is the only one of the Great Lakes that has no Canadian waters?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81cc8d0de9af39e9d4688", "question": "As of 2020, who was the only president to be awarded the Purple Heart?", "answer": "John F Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f7d3fe83fe1f2a824c27", "question": "A young women in the 1920's that behaved and dressed boldly was referred to as what?", "answer": "A flapper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017385344491cbd7c5a1798", "question": "During what years were Thomas Jefferson nickels made with siver?", "answer": "1942 to 1945 -- Due to a wartime shortage of nickel metal, nickel coins were minted using 35% silver, 56% copper and 9% manganese.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cb", "question": "Who won an Oscar for \"Best Actress\" for her role in \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339011", "question": "Which famous painting was stolen from an Oslo museum in 1994?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2aa", "question": "What nation was led by Akbar the Great?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e3", "question": "What year was the first Amazon Kindle device introduced?", "answer": "2007", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0da64fcbed638185eaa03", "question": "What country is known for the art of water puppetry?", "answer": "Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c063", "question": "In 1892, 15-year-old Alonzo \"Lonnie\" Clayton became the youngest winner of which sporting event?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133899f", "question": "What term is used to describe the art of folding paper sculptures?", "answer": "Origami", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dde", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"mammoth\"?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ea", "question": "What is the most general and highest taxonomy rank of organisms?", "answer": "Domain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0d", "question": "What is the fear of fog known as?", "answer": "Homichlophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907b", "question": "What is the meaning of the Latin phrase \"cum grano salis\"?", "answer": "With a grain of salt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47e", "question": "What is the capital of Vermont?", "answer": "Montpelier", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf9", "question": "N'Djamena is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f4e3fa5fdd6dd25324e8", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the west?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ca28877e98cb97778a03", "question": "In what sea would you find the Admiralty Islands?", "answer": "Bismarck Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b712", "question": "Which New York newspaper wrote \"yes Virginia, there is a Santa Claus\"?", "answer": "The New York Sun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2592731a458464a93c46a", "question": "In what year was the NERF football created?", "answer": "1972 by former Minnesota Vikings' kicker Fred Cox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc28", "question": "What year was Martha Stewart born?", "answer": "1941", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071eeb3745b36be73039e6", "question": "Which young girl comes back to life early on in the \"Revival\" comic book series?", "answer": "Jordan Borchardt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede6396ce05a3942286df9", "question": "In the film \"Home Alone,\" where was the Christmas vacation to be held?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69ae020565ad31a57c757", "question": "What was the first non-axis jet plane to see combat?", "answer": "Gloster Meteor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86a", "question": "What is the Syrah grape called in Australia?", "answer": "Shiraz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc1bb6de0eb824d4052e2", "question": "What Islands make up the U.S. Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The U.S. Virgin Islands consist of Saint Croix, Saint Thomas, Saint John, and Water Island, alongside 50 other tiny islets.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6000ee169a72b906b34e3cf4", "question": "What is the medical term for labored breathing which is derived from the Greek for \"bad breath\"?", "answer": "Dyspnoea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8d47f2b42d4a3561a9efa", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ea", "question": "What TV show began with the words \"There is nothing wrong with your television set.\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a85", "question": "Who flew from England to America in a giant peach carried by seagulls?", "answer": "James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c5", "question": "Who shot President James Garfield?", "answer": "Charles J. Guiteau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3ee638b5801b8f54a7fb7", "question": "Which was the last major offensive operation undertaken by elite German paratroopers in World War II?", "answer": "Attack against Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929e", "question": "In \"Ferris Bueller's Day Off\", who is the \"Sausage King of Chicago\"?", "answer": "Abe Froman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febba037e83c707845b2142", "question": "What is the object that opposing players must destroy in order to win at \"League of Legends\"?", "answer": "Nexus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58b", "question": "How many time zones does the state of Florida span?", "answer": "2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde5297c6c6b019850c9a97", "question": "What was the motto of the Hitler Youth in World War II?", "answer": "Blood and Honor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a6", "question": "What is the axilla better known as?", "answer": "Armpit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b558", "question": "How many beans of coffee are needed to make an espresso?", "answer": "42", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77379eec85e375820b309", "question": "Where is the Archipelago Sea?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacb", "question": "What is the International Criminal Police Organization better known as?", "answer": "Interpol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ece", "question": "Achilles' heel was the result of him being dipped in what mythical river?", "answer": "The Styx", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aedd", "question": "Who was president of the US from 1953 to 1961?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bfe0045b668d7dfe168b5c0", "question": "Which desert is located in the southeastern part of California?", "answer": "The Mojave desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c860", "question": "What animal is also called a wildebeest?", "answer": "Gnu", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59523ef3736d4be723796b55", "question": "What type of interchange, that is widely used in North America and in some parts of Europe, did the Ontario Ministry of Transportation invent?", "answer": "Partial cloverleaf interchange, or Parclo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a83", "question": "Which original \"Star Trek\" character was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ad", "question": "Construction of the Colosseum began under the ruling of which emperor?", "answer": "Vespasian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b9", "question": "In which US state is the geographic center of the 48 contiguous states?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7f", "question": "What animator created and provided the voices for Beavis & Butthead?", "answer": "Mike Judge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cf16bb53d1af658864f2", "question": "Who does an angel placed on top of the Christmas tree represent?", "answer": "Archangel Gabriel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f74dfa9e54d890926f701", "question": "According to Russian law, a homeless person must be where after 10 pm?", "answer": "At home", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb9d27e83c707845b2140", "question": "Helminthology is the study of what?", "answer": "Worms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa4066ce05a3942286eaf", "question": "What famous actor was once a swimming instructor for the Army?", "answer": "Clint Eastwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938f", "question": "What role did James Dean play in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "Jim Stark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a19", "question": "What UK band had a #1 hit in 1981 with the song \"Don\u2019t You Want Me\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b7", "question": "Nicole Kidman voiced a character named Norma-Jean in what animated movie?", "answer": "Happy Feet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e7fb06d333868d34d746", "question": "In the Book of Esther, which adviser to the King of Persia suggests exiling Queen Vashti?", "answer": "Memukan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb16e65ff7d326b622a6a", "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Southern hemisphere?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921ff04a4edfd43a087add3", "question": "Which scientist wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hawking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a666", "question": "What US city is home to the International UFO Museum and Research Center?", "answer": "Roswell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71a", "question": "What planet's four largest moons are collectively known as the Galilean Moons?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59412872bab1e6f9796f1b5d", "question": "Who composed \"Symphonie fantastique\"?", "answer": "Hector Berlioz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bc84d96d05b23b281656", "question": "Who captured and murdered the Inca Emperor Atahualpa?", "answer": "Francisco Pizarro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c000", "question": "Which vegetable is used if a dish is described as \"a la Crecy\"?", "answer": "Carrots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a2b012f2a7826b9b871f", "question": "Which modern artist created the \"Mother and Child Divided\"?", "answer": "Damien Hirst", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906f", "question": "What US state are a large portion of Stephen King's novels based in?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0f", "question": "What did American patriots dump into Boston Harbor in 1773 to protest British import taxes?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab55", "question": "What is the second largest country in South America?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f5", "question": "What animal has been called the \u201cpoor man\u2019s cow\u201d?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00f", "question": "What is the female version of the Duke title?", "answer": "Duchess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cd", "question": "What country is sometimes called the Land of Fire and Ice?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d2", "question": "What word is used for a male deer?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd56", "question": "The Peabody Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Radio and television", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20c", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb8b07e83c707845b2135", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc79", "question": "What company's famous plaid pattern is called \"novacheck\"?", "answer": "Burberry's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071df63745b36be73039e0", "question": "What is the name of the first Lunar Module to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4a7649076251badbeab6", "question": "Who patented the concept of a flat engine in 1896?", "answer": "Karl Benz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76e9beec85e375820b2de", "question": "What is the biggest country without a river?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6d", "question": "Liege municipality is located in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded148ea2747c8aff16d31", "question": "What Hebrew word means \"so be it\"?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cb", "question": "In networking, what does the abbreviation \"DSL\" stand for?", "answer": "Digital Subscriber Line", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73e", "question": "What was the name of the first nuclear-powered submarine?", "answer": "USS Nautilus SSN-571", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af2", "question": "Pablo Picasso was one of the suspects questioned when what item was stole in Paris in 1911?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067ddfff9c0647b50a8075", "question": "What soccer team won the 2016 FIFA Club World Cup?", "answer": "Real Madrid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aae", "question": "Who wrote, The Christmas Letters: A Novella in 1996", "answer": "Lee Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01f", "question": "What was the last name of husband and wife Julius and Ethel, executed for treason in 1953?", "answer": "Rosenberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1cb", "question": "What primary alcohols go into the standard Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Menthe and Creme de Cacao", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980d", "question": "What pop star's first and middle names are Katherine Dawn?", "answer": "KD Lang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3572ff048f679a45ab02", "question": "What color is Mars\u2019 sunset?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdf", "question": "What is the last name of the founder of the Papa John's pizza chain?", "answer": "Schnatter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a847", "question": "What is the name of the seismic fault line located at the conjunction of Missouri, Arkansas, and Tennessee?", "answer": "New Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35c", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc2", "question": "What country borders Albania to the south?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e93e06d333868d34d753", "question": "Where is the mythological birthplace of the Incas?", "answer": "Isla del Sol, Bolivia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a392", "question": "What was renamed to Ho Chi Minh City in 1975?", "answer": "Saigon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c2474f032c0db195b480", "question": "What U.S. President worked as a lifeguard?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan was a lifeguard during high school", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cb", "question": "Which Oscar Wilde character stayed young as his picture aged?", "answer": "Dorian Gray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a37", "question": "Which French term literally means \"Fat Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Mardi Gras", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a123", "question": "What are the escape tunnels in the film \"The Great Escape\" called?", "answer": "Tom, Dick and Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e5", "question": "What was the second country to be featured in the \"Michelin Guide\" in 1904?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a227", "question": "What year did Puff Daddy record the song \"I'll Be Missing You\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98c", "question": "What musical instrument is played to wake up soldiers?", "answer": "Bugle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febad6c7e83c707845b20f3", "question": "What is the technical term for jet lag?", "answer": "Desynchronosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1af", "question": "Despite filing to patent the first electric razor in 1928, when did Jacob Schick actually receive a patent?", "answer": "1930", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bae", "question": "What was the last name of the main family on the TV show \"3rd Rock From the Sun\"?", "answer": "Solomon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba3", "question": "Who wrote the play, \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7f", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Abe Ravelstein in the novel \"Ravelstein\"?", "answer": "Allan Bloom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008c40cf842fa4c4ba969e", "question": "With which horror film series would you associate the character Leatherface?", "answer": "Texas Chainsaw Massacre", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ce32877e98cb97778a3e", "question": "The famous commercial port of Sidon is located in which Arab country?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf02", "question": "What animal is the mascot of the US Naval Academy?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d37", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Jed Clampett\"?", "answer": "Flatt and Scruggs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1a", "question": "A lock of what composer's hair was sold at one of Sotheby's Auctions?", "answer": "Beethoven's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d5", "question": "What European city is known as the \"Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59decedfea2747c8aff16d18", "question": "What did Lorraine Chase famously advertise on TV?", "answer": "Campari", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3c", "question": "What year was actor Anthony Hopkins born?", "answer": "1937", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390af", "question": "What year was the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\" first published?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b989", "question": "What is a \u2018half hunter\u2019?", "answer": "A pocket watch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc5546ce05a3942286f3b", "question": "What is a pli\u00e9 in ballet?", "answer": "Bending at the knees", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd3", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Hippomenes also known as?", "answer": "Melanion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b0", "question": "In what city would you find Tivoli Gardens?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b775", "question": "What is a brigand?", "answer": "An armed bandit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c871", "question": "What two elements make up water?", "answer": "Hydrogen and oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7f", "question": "Who wrote \"Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddac06ce05a3942286d89", "question": "Red attributes his nickname, \"Red\" to he being what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red told Andy he picked up the nickname due to his being Irish.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c687", "question": "What is the average lifespan of the hummingbird?", "answer": "5 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a645", "question": "Which US state is known as the \"Land of Lincoln\"?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe735c8eec85e375820b251", "question": "Who said, \"A pessimist sees the difficulty in every opportunity; an optimist sees the opportunity in every difficulty.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a1", "question": "In 1918, Woodrow Wilson addressed Congress with a speech laying out how many points?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88b", "question": "What is the point value of the letter Z in a standard Scrabble game?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e0", "question": "Which country owns the Canary Islands?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b584", "question": "What is the name for Argentinean cowboys?", "answer": "Gauchos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f0b4fe83fe1f2a824c12", "question": "At the Seder table, people eat and drink in a reclining position. What does this represent?", "answer": "Freedom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d34", "question": "The novel \"Pride and Prejudice\" follows the story of what five sisters?", "answer": "Jane, Elizabeth, Mary, Kitty and Lydia Bennet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c401", "question": "A male horse is known as a colt until it reaches what age?", "answer": "Five", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f96", "question": "What two words were tattooed on Robert Mitchum's knuckles in \"The Night of the Hunter\"?", "answer": "Love and Hate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3e", "question": "What was the name of Michael Jackson's pet chimpanzee?", "answer": "Bubbles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0b", "question": "The TV series \"NCIS\" was a spin-off from what other series?", "answer": "JAG", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ec", "question": "What is the study of production of materials at low temperatures called?", "answer": "Cryogenics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5971df1189261e916c8e09a6", "question": "What is the name of Batman's Butler?", "answer": "Alfred", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339692", "question": "Who replaced Michael Keaton as Batman in the movie series by the same name?", "answer": "Val Kilmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989d", "question": "What TV sitcom followed the lives of June, Ward, Wally and Theodore?", "answer": "Leave It To Beaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab06", "question": "What was Genghis Khan's birth name?", "answer": "Temujin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ddc1fe83fe1f2a824b62", "question": "What color was long considered the color of royalty?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e7", "question": "What tree measurement do foresters usually make at 4 feet above ground level?", "answer": "Girth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935f", "question": "What was in the jaws of the swordfish mounted on the wall in the Addams Family house?", "answer": "A human leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3a63ff048f679a45ab2b", "question": "What does the human lacrimal gland produce?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded197ea2747c8aff16d34", "question": "Vodka and coffee liqueur make what cocktail?", "answer": "Black Russian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72c", "question": "What \"h\"\u00adword is the unit of measurement used to determine the height of a horse?", "answer": "Hand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6a", "question": "Who replaces Professor Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e38ce17f6c8a670a7957c52", "question": "What is Jean Valjean's prison number in the novel \"Les Miserables\"?", "answer": "24601", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae9384574a5ce6b56b823d", "question": "Who was the only man to knock out Muhammad Ali in a heavyweight title fight?", "answer": "Larry Holmes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ad", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa42b5c73aa70ea0b70b14", "question": "Fort-de-France is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Martinique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3dc", "question": "What became the second independent country in the Americas after the United States?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feccf31ec223966ae8f88b3", "question": "What is the name of Holly's cat in \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Cat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1936682715b82711ce2", "question": "The fear of fire is known as what?", "answer": "Pyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e6", "question": "What two states share a border with Florida?", "answer": "Alabama and Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdda", "question": "Ash Wednesday marks the first day of what?", "answer": "Lent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa5e673838c5c8a417f2c", "question": "The aardvark is native to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e03", "question": "What occupation is shared by TV protagonists Sean McNamara and Christian Troy?", "answer": "Plastic surgeon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339961", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Milhouse's last name?", "answer": "Van Houten", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddcad6ce05a3942286d9e", "question": "Who hosts the Potterwatch pirate radio show?", "answer": "Lee Jordan hosts Potterwatch to advise listeners on defenses against Lord Voldemort.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a7", "question": "What George Orwell book foresees Oceania, Eurasia and Eastasia?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a391", "question": "What is the capital of Ireland?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968e", "question": "Who received an Oscar for directing the 1986 movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Oliver Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008b07cf842fa4c4ba9695", "question": "Alex Raymond created which comic strip character in 1934?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7abb856490a8cc1a6e5297", "question": "What are the six types of quarks more generally referred to as?", "answer": "Flavors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339771", "question": "Which actor plays Tony Montana in Scarface?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c7944f0f6af5b066631", "question": "Ranidaphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Frogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c834", "question": "Seafloor spreading at midoceanic ridges is how scientists first discovered the periodic reversal of what?", "answer": "The earth's magnetic field", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f68", "question": "In 2006, what song became the first British single to top the US charts in almost a decade?", "answer": "You're Beautiful", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3d77ff048f679a45ab4e", "question": "A unit of measure of absorbed radiation is known as what?", "answer": "Rad", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18a", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Nine Tonight\"?", "answer": "Bob Seger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a997", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Krakatoa\"?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ac", "question": "What New York City landmark is nicknamed \"The Crossroads of the World\"?", "answer": "Times Square", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2581931a458464a93c464", "question": "What is a bonbonni\u00e8re?", "answer": "A fancy box or dish used to hold bonbons.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56b", "question": "What is Lipton the world's biggest-selling brand of?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8be1ec223966ae8f8844", "question": "Which television series revolves around a concierge doctor making house calls in the Hamptons?", "answer": "\"Royal Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e7", "question": "Who played the judge in the TV show \"Night Court\"?", "answer": "Harry Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5be", "question": "Who is the inventor of Coca Cola?", "answer": "John Pemerton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a2", "question": "Who released the hit single \"Barbie Girl\" in 1997?", "answer": "Aqua", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ef", "question": "What actor was the executive producer of the mystery series \"Push, Nevada\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d077d1a1c922dd1ac64b9", "question": "What term is used for the speed at which a piece of music is played?", "answer": "Tempo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4b", "question": "What movie was Robert Downey Jr.'s first movie?", "answer": "Pound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339921", "question": "Actress Carrie Fisher and singer Edie Brickell have both been married to what musician?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3a", "question": "What was World War I known as before World War II?", "answer": "The Great War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe699b720565ad31a57c74a", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cdf", "question": "The poet Ogden Nash wrote \"Candy is dandy, but liquor is...\" what?", "answer": "Quicker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a793", "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is considered to be part of which geographical region?", "answer": "Caribbean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Apu's last name?", "answer": "Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a0", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the sun?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597ddb6777980686f722d176", "question": "What year was the first patent for a pencil sharpener applied for?", "answer": "1828", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab2", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Belarus?", "answer": "White stork", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1c", "question": "What classic sitcom character was played by Irene Ryan from 1962 to 1971?", "answer": "Granny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b522", "question": "What popular operating system are the Mac OS X series based on?", "answer": "Unix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adfd", "question": "What decade introduced barcode scanners to supermarkets?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bf", "question": "In which Mega Man game can you acquire the Gemini Laser?", "answer": "Mega Man 3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a1266c0f9723ab15cb37", "question": "How much time passed between the invention of cans and can openers?", "answer": "48 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6f03a9e54d890926f6cd", "question": "What country is home to the world's most rapidly-constructed skyscraper?", "answer": "China -- Broad Sustainable Building company built a 57-story building called Mini Sky City in 19 days using prefab components.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa43", "question": "What geographic term describes a hill with sharply sloping sides and a flat top?", "answer": "Butte", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e2", "question": "In sports, what does IIHF stand for?", "answer": "International Ice Hockey Federation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973b", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the band CCR?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea45c0ff048f679a45ab98", "question": "What digestive tract illness often is a manifestation of diabetes?", "answer": "Gastroparesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02e", "question": "What decade saw the introduction of the Easy\u00adBake Oven, Lite Brite, and Spirograph?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb97", "question": "What type of building or facility gets its name from the Greek meaning \"to exercise naked\"?", "answer": "Gymnasium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0e52cfcbed638185eaa2b", "question": "The Yalu River separates China from which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b50", "question": "What was the name of Derek Zoolander's rival male model, played by Owen Wilson, in the 2001 movie \"Zoolander\"?", "answer": "Hansel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339535", "question": "Who played Lois in \"Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman\"?", "answer": "Teri Hatcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc9176de0eb824d405301", "question": "Where is the New York City Marathon start line?", "answer": "Staten Island -- It starts at the base of the Verrazano-Narrows Bridge in Staten Island and ends in Central Park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84d", "question": "What sea borders Iran to the north?", "answer": "Caspian Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173fb844491cbd7c5a17b5", "question": "What was created by the people who produced the academic journal called the\u00a0\"Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists\" in 1947?", "answer": "The Doomsday Clock -- It was created after humanity entered the Nuclear Age after the dropping of atomic bombs on Japan in 1945.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49d", "question": "Why were the 1916 Olympic Games cancelled?", "answer": "Due to World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399cf", "question": "What famous blind musician has the real given last name Judkins?", "answer": "Stevie Wonder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc0666de0eb824d4052d9", "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?", "answer": "Sidney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071d823745b36be73039d9", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cd40e06685cf15b733e9896", "question": "In fencing what is the name of the action when two fencers make physical contact with any part of their bodies (or hilts)?", "answer": "Corps-a-corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339215", "question": "Who voiced Rocky in the movie \"Chicken Run\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ae", "question": "A Capuchin is a species of what type of animal?", "answer": "Monkey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc6", "question": "What was the name of the ship that Jason & his Argonauts sail in?", "answer": "Argo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72b", "question": "How do Japanese children refer to Santa Claus?", "answer": "Santa no ojisan or Uncle Santa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339904", "question": "What TV show title character was played by pop singer Brandy?", "answer": "Moesha", "category": "entertainment"}]